In this episode of Detail, if I'm LeBron James, and if I'm Kevin Durant, I'm looking for
areas on the floor where I can attack in 1-2 dribble pull-up situations.
Get to the spot before defenses can key on me and lock in on me and operate quickly.
It's another great opportunity right there.
Now, this is the right pass to make.
It's a right pass to make. No doubt about it.
He's open. I'll just throw it off target.
But what I also have are these pull-up jump shots.
I mean, my size and my body keeps the defense off balance.
I mean, look at Bell here. He's completely turned around.
I can stop on a dime and pull up and shoot that jumper right there.
1-2 dribble pull-ups.
I can do 1-2 dribble pull-ups all series long.
All series long.
There, there, stop, pop.
This is where I can make a living.
These actions right here, these quick pin downs, catching and shooting, right?
1 dribble, stop, pop.
The more I have to play with the ball, the more Cleveland's defense can lock in on me.
But these actions here, bang, bang.
I mean, that's easy money.
I got to be looking for these here.
I shouldn't be looking to score when I'm handling the ball away from the rim.
If I got to bounce the ball three, four, five times, that's where Cleveland's defense can load up.
If I'm looking to get buckets, I got to get buckets off of action like this.
With the size that KD has, the size that LeBron has,
they'll be able to elevate over any double team and shoot that shot
and not have to go all the way into the basket and deal with trees and charges and no foul calls.
But get to those spots and pull up for that jumper.
For more analysis, go to detail on ESPN+.