If I'm Jason Tatum, I'm looking at ways to improve my game.
I'm really good at posting up.
I'm really good in isolation.
I'm really good at creating opportunities.
But where I could get better is the opportunities
to catch and shoot.
I'm popping out to catch, right?
I'm catching, I'm looking to attack off the catch.
I think I can do a better job of sliding away quicker
and right into a shot.
All right, so if I'm moving faster here,
I slide into this little pocket area.
Move, don't let the catch the ball here.
Curl off, slide right into this pocket area,
just underneath Banes.
That should be a good catch and shoot opportunity, right?
Because if you see Nance is playing off, right?
He's protecting against penetration.
So if I'm able to slide off of this
and come down into this pocket here,
so you can't throw that pass right now
because I don't want to catch it there.
I want to catch it right here in this pocket here, right?
So I'm hiding behind Banes so my man can't get to me.
He's got a bad angle to get to me, right?
So that frees me up for a second
to be able to shoot that jump shot.
So I curl around that, slide into this pocket,
and that should be a jump shot
because Nance is not playing me to catch and shoot.
He's playing me to drive, right?
He's cushioning.
So I got to get into that pocket
and look for that jump shot.
No, this would be a bucket.
I'm coming out too wide here.
That's a jump shot right there.
Hide behind that screen.
If I come up too high here,
I give my man a right angle to get to me, right?
Coming up here, that's the right, he can close out to me.
Instead of being here, if I move back just a little bit,
just behind the screen, he can't get to me.
I know he's cheating it, right?
So he's trying to shortcut it.
So when he tries to shortcut it,
it's important that I hide right behind that screen there.
You simplify the game, simplify the game, catch and shoot.
But coming all the way out here at this angle
makes it very easy for the defense to close out to me.
But if I can drop my catch down
and catch it just behind the screen,
instead of catching it out here,
now that should be an open opportunity.
Should be an easy catch and shoot right there.
So to learn from some of the players
that came before me,
I'd probably look at Richard Hamilton
when he was with the Detroit Pistons
and how he used these screens a lot,
and how he moved without the ball
and how he got himself into these little pocket areas
off the screen to be able to catch and shoot.
Understanding how his defender's playing him,
to be able to curl off of an action
and get back door layups.
But simplifying the game by using the screen off the ball
to put myself in pockets to be able to catch and shoot.
If I could figure out how to do that with my game,
it'll take my game to another level.
It'll make us a better team, and the sky's the limit.
For more analysis, go to detail on ESPN Plus.