On this episode of Detail, I will break down how Trey Young needs to read the game as if it's a chessboard.
Understanding how to put defenses in a position where it's a lose-lose.
Are you going to stay with the shooter or are you going to leave the shooter
and open up opportunities for elbow jumpers and layups at the rim?
Stay with the shooter and you open up diving opportunities and weakside three opportunities.
Here, zip that ball right over the top. This defender has his hands down.
Got to zip that ball right to this big over the top.
The more I can establish early that I'm going to make these passes on these plays,
the more it frees me up to score during the season.
Here we go off of this action right now. There's nobody back there.
This defensive player has his hands down and zip that ball right over the top here to the big.
Let them finish at the rim. Or if that's a tough pass, for example, say you're playing against
a team where this big has his hands up high. He's not going to let me throw that ball over the
top. Then what I need to do is come off of this screen here, zip that ball to the corner
and now the pass goes corner into this big diving boom boom bucket against really good
defensive teams. Now we got to go corner, hit the big diving boom. This little guy is going
to pull over the help. That's fine. The big catches it. The big fires it here for a shot.
Boom boom right. Got to be able to play the games and sequences of options.
Here again, same action. This is the basic read that I'm going to do all season long.
Coming off of this dribble handoff action, I'll be able to make this read all season.
It's a very basic and simple one. How a team is going to play it.
This team's in a drop coverage. Okay, they're in a drop coverage. Then my read is exactly
the same. I come off. I keep my dribble alive. I keep this defender on my back.
I occupy this real estate. Make this big play me.
This big dives and now the big has to make a decision. It's the same play as before.
This big has to make a decision. He dives. This big stays with me. That means I have the big
diving at the rim for a lob. This player pulls in. This player should be deep corner.
Has to be deep corner. Spacing is off here. They're mucking up this area here.
He needs to slide deep corner. Now the dive occurs. This weak side defender pulls in to help.
Now this player shakes up to where he is. Now there's the pass.
So I can come off. Here's the handle. The big stays with me. Make the pass to the big.
The big lays it up. Or here's the help. Big makes the pass to the corner for three.
Now if I keep the dribble alive and the big decides not to stay with me,
he goes with the big diving to the basket. Now that's an easy money jumper for me at the elbow.
That's easy. That's a layup.
And as Trey Young progresses from college to the pros, it becomes more important to understand
the strategy of the game before the game takes place. And that can only be done with
film work, constant study, and attention to detail. For more analysis, go to detail on ESPN+.