In this episode of detail I will be breaking down how Jewel Lloyd can take her game to yet another level
How to hide behind screens how to attack the ball on defense as well as how to manipulate screen roll coverages
All right for timing sake
This screen needs to be held a little longer
I know we want to slip out quick, but it needs to hold that screen just a little bit longer
Hold it just a little bit longer
Right because it's a timing thing
Right she holds that screen a little bit longer now here. I am coming off
And y'all spacing needs to be a little bit better
She should be down in the corner and now that frees up Brianna to step right there in that hole
She steps in a hole now. She hits the slip
Right because as it is right now that the spacing is so congested in here to make that pass
It's too congested. She's got to be down in the corner on a weak side
And now we can go boom boom
Another possible option to look at especially when you know you're facing this kind of coverage is to prove Brianna high now
Keep the weak side in the corner
So now Brianna is high that removes the help here
Right and now in this rotation. Here's the show. I can pivot back around hit Sue in a corner
Now Sue can go corner in
Right because this helped player here. We're removing because Brianna now is up high
So now you remove that rotation. So now I come off
Pivot back around make a nice left-handed pass here to Sue. Sue then hits the diver
Got him right gotta stop here. I got to see that here I come
Being chased. I see she's shortcutting stop right here
Stop right here. That ball gets passed right there. I catch one dribble. I'm at the room
All right, catch. I can pirouette
Be right at the room right instead of coming all the way out here. There's no need
She's already beat right now that pass gets made one dribble at the room
It's easy money
For more analysis go to detail on ESPN plus