Welcome to the Muse Cage Basketball Network.
The Golden Democracy.
84 assists on 135 field goals through 3 games.
Every team wants to play team ball.
But let's look at how Golden State does it.
What do you notice Draymond doing upon receiving the ball?
Is he looking to make a play for himself?
Or is he looking to make a play for someone else?
The way Golden State plays is rarer.
The players go into attack mode when they are off the ball.
Not on the ball.
They don't force you to defend 1v1.
They force you to defend 3v3.
They force you to cover split actions, rip actions,
handoff actions, curl actions, slice actions, just to name a few.
Playing this style takes advantage of the basic human challenge of communication.
Can you have the presence of mind to know who was setting the screen?
Have the presence of mind to know who was coming off the screen?
Have the presence of mind to communicate the proper strategy to your teammate involved in the screen?
And have the presence of mind to communicate crystal clearly while 20,000 fans scream at the top of their lungs?
And do it at split second.
This is what makes them so hard to contain for 48 minutes.
Having to be in constant communication defensively while dealing with the conditioning and physicality of the game wears teams down.
It's hard to talk when you're out of breath, right?
Now imagine trying to communicate while at the same time being hit with screen after screen after screen after screen after screen after screen after screen.
Yes, they have great individual scores, but those scores are never stagnant.
They are constantly looking for each other, screening for each other, and passing to each other,
taking advantage of every defensive mistake.
These mistakes are built on lack of communication.
Lack of communication creates division.
Division breaks teams apart.
A team apart can't play as one.
If you can't play as one, your season is done.
Long live the Golden Democracy.