In this episode of detail I would really look at defending the ball more aggressively
or having a clear direction or focus of where I want to push the ball handler.
Too many times I'm giving direct line drives to ball handlers and I'm putting our defense in jeopardy.
All right this is a threatening position.
They say on those uh shark shows when a shark's swimming with his fins down you know he's in an
attack position right you know James is not backing his ball up right he's staying in an
attack position here so you know this is a threatening posture and so to move closer to him
does nothing but put us in jeopardy because from here he's going to attack
and now I'm opening up that tight turn again to get to that basket see if he turns the corner
like that then you know Igadala I mean there's nothing he can do I'm giving him a straight line
to that basket so when I when he's here in this position here I have to be able to force him
if you drew an imaginary line between me and Igadala that's the angle where I need to push
harden I cannot allow him to turn this corner if he dips his shoulder and turns this corner
we're done right and me trying to hold him there with my right hand that that is that's
not going to do anything with this guy I mean he's going to go right through that
he's looking to attack me right so I got a cushion again same thing get off my heels cushion
where am I sending him right but again that's a direct line drive right that's a direct line
drive I got to be able to guard him you know these teams need to know that they're not just
going to be able to just isolate me and have something positive come out of it
I have to be able to guard this player and force him to help right not allow him to
just simply turn the corner and do this
I need to be able to hold my ground defensively I need to be mindful of where the help is
and I need to be mindful of how to push the ball handler in the direction of where that help is
and prohibit him from turning the corner quickly which you know makes the weak side help and
consequential for more analysis go to detail on ESPN plus