So on this here, I like to see him take his time more.
He's got more time.
I mean, the thing that we have to remember as offensive players when we
hit game winners is that the defense has been conditioned and told by the coach
repeatedly in the time out, do not foul shooters.
Do not foul shooters.
All right, so that means he's not going to go for a block.
Not in a serious way, anyway, because he's scared that he may foul you.
So you can take your time.
You got plenty of time here.
You got three point, is that one seconds?
You got plenty of time to set your feet and shoot that shot, right?
See, look at the defense.
He's not leaving his feet, right?
He's just going to put a hand up like that, right?
So you don't have to worry about it.
You don't even have to rush.
I mean, Kwai's got enough time here to even pump,
fake, and take one dribble around them.
You got plenty of time.
Look at that.
That's 2.4 seconds on that clock.
You got plenty, plenty, plenty, plenty of time.
You can pump, fake that, escape, dribble, pull up, and shoot.
You can take your time, get your feet set, pull up, and shoot.
They're not going to foul you in that situation on game winners.
I mean, again, that's how Virginia found themselves in finals.
So if I'm Kwai, the player that I'm looking at the most
is Michael Jordan.
Game one had about one offensive rebound.
When you look at that and you say, OK, that's not really important,
but it is, because offensive rebounds
create a fight within the team.
And you saw Michael fighting for those offensive rebounds
all the time, fighting through bigs,
really mucking it up, down low, and resisting.
That adds a culture and adds a toughness to your team
and the playoffs.
And the value of that I cannot overestimate.
It is so critical to be able to add that personality,
particularly in the playoffs and Kwai's strength and size.
That's how you get a lot of easy buckets
is by crashing those offensive boards
and fighting for every single possession,
the same way Michael used to.